翻译校对       Mam
日  听      マキ
日听校对       Syura
翻译        银苹果
时间轴       卡卡
压制      娜夏
OP&ED       葉隠
Syura
诸神字幕组
Now you've done it.
やってしまった
It's done, all right.
やっちゃったね
It's not our fault.
僕ら知～らない
Y-you idiots! You're the ones
who bumped into it, right?
バ…バカもの
お前らがぶつかってきたんだろうが
That's just because
Haruhi was running away.
だってハルヒが逃げるんだもん
We wanted to have some fun,
by having her do a little cosplay.
せっかくコスプレさせて楽しく遊ぼうと思ったのに
We're always doing cosplay, you know!
コスプレなら いつもやっているだろ
Not the usual Host Club kind.
いつものホスト部のやつじゃなくて
This time in a bunny girl costume-
disguised as a girl.
これはバニーガールの衣装
女装だよ
Disguised as a girl?
女装…って…
"She is a girl..."
You'd want to see that too, right, sir?
見たいでしょう 殿も
"The Theatre of Tamaki's Mind"
I'd definitely want
to see that, all right.
確かに見たいわ
No, but this isn't the time for that!
いや しかし 今はそんな状況では…
And where do you get off trying to
take advantage of this commotion!?
つーか お前ら どさくさに紛れて その手はなんだ
Get away from Haruhi!
ハルヒから 離れろう
No way!
いやだよ
Guys, there aren't any guests here,
お前ら お客さまもいないし  騒ぐのは一向にかまわんが
so I don't mind at all
if you make a racket,
but are you sure you want to?
You'll wake Honey- senpai.
いいのか ハニー先輩が起きるぞ
High school 3rd-Year,
and he's still taking naps?
高三にもなって昼寝ですか
Well, we can't help that
his bunny has been stained.
まぁ 汚してしまったものは仕方ないです
Let's wake him up and frankly apologize.
起こして素直に謝りましょう
Wait! Don't go near Honey- senpai!
待って ハニー先輩に近づくな
早く こっちに避難しろ
Hurry, come take shelter over here!
What do you mean?
なんですか
Honey- senpai wakes up
in a megaton-class ill humor.
ハニー先輩は 寝起きがメガトン級に悪い
これはあくまで噂だが
This is just a rumor,
but once, when the Haninozuka family
visited a U.S. military installation,
米軍の訓練施設に
埴之塚家が格闘技の特別指導に訪れた時
to give hand-to-hand combat
technique training,
Honey- senpai is said to have slept
the whole time, due to jet lag.
時差ぼけでハニー先輩はずっと眠っていたらしい
Hey, master, are you okay?
Hey master Are you OK?
Hey master Hey master
And when one soldier carelessly
tried to wake up Honey- senpai,
そしていつまでも眠っていたハニー先輩を
since he had been sleeping so long...
軍人の一人が迂闊にも起こしてしまうと
I'm still sleepy...
I'm still sleeping
Oh My God
Two unfortunate platoons
of green beret special forces
哀れ 特殊部隊グリーンベレー二個小隊はハニー先輩に秒殺され
were wiped out in seconds
by Honey- senpai,
and ever since, they say there have
been diplomatic issues with America.
その後 アメリカとの外交問題に発展したといわれている
It's terrifying...
恐ろしい
What's worse, I've heard
that Usa-chan was handmade
しかも このウサちゃんは
ハニー先輩が大好きだった亡きグランマのお手製ということだ
by Honey- senpai's favorite late grandma.
Judging by the way he
always carries it with him,
常に持っていることから見ても
there can be little doubt that
it's a precious article to him.
大事な品であることは間違いあるまい
Once he wakes up, and sees
his Usa-chan irrevocably altered...
そんなウサちゃんの変わり果てた姿を寝起きに見せたりしたら…
He's going to irrevocably alter us, too!
俺たちが変わり果てた姿に…
You're exaggerating.
大げさな
どう考えても嘘っぽいでしょう その噂
Any way you think about them,
those stories ring false.
No, there is other evidence
that Honey- senpai
いや ハニー先輩が邪悪な二重人格である証拠ならほかにもあるぞ
has an evil split personality.
Honey- senpai is type AB.
ハニー先輩はAB型だ
So?
だから？
つまり 鏡夜と同じ血液型だ
That means...
...he has the same blood type as Kyoya!
"Incredibly persuasive!!"
Do you have some sort of
problem with my blood type?
俺の血液型に何か問題でも？
Oh, those of you watching who are
type AB, please don't get upset.
これ見てるAB型の人 怒らないでくださいねぇ
This is bad. We have to do
something before he wakes up.
まずいぞ 目覚める前に手を打たねば…
- Hikaru, Kaoru...
- Sir!
光 馨
Get your folks' Cessna.
お前らんちのセスナを出せ
Fly to Osorezan,
and bring back a medium.
恐山に飛んで イタコをお連れしろ
We'll have her channel
Honey- senpai's grandma,
ハニー先輩のグランマを口寄せしていただいて
and make us a new Usa-chan.
新たのウサちゃんを作ってもらうのだ
この青森県の地図を持ってゆけ
Take this map of
Aomori Prefecture with you.
Don't forget the apple juice, apple jam,
and Nebuta doll souvenirs!
お土産にリンゴジュースとリンゴジャム
それにねぶた人形を忘れるなよ
そんな時間ないだろう
We don't have that much time.
錯乱しててもいいから もっと建設的なこと言ってよ
We don't mind the derangement,
but please come up with
something more constructive.
All right, let's go with this: While we
send Usa-chan out for cleaning, Haruhi,
ではこうしよう
ウサちゃんをクリーニングに出す間
you wear this fur suit.
ハルヒ この着ぐるみに入れ
Nice idea!
ナイスアイディア
"The Theatre of Tamaki
and the Twins' Minds"
No way!
イヤです
And for that matter,
where did you get that thing!?
大体どっから持ってきたんですか こんなの
It's too obvious!
バレバレですよ
It's okay. How can he tell such a
slight difference with half-awake eyes?
大丈夫だ
寝ぼけた目では 少しの違いなど分かるものか
Then, Senpai, you wear it!
なら 先輩が入ってくださいよ
It won't be cute if I wear it!
We've given up on the bunny girl thing,
俺が入っても 可愛くないだろ
バニーガールは諦めたから
so now you can be a real rabbit, instead!
Be a real rabbit, instead!
本物のウサギになって見せるがよい
なって見せるがよい
"Incomprehensible"
いや いかん 間に合わん
Oh, no! It's too late! There's no other
choice but to use another substitute!
仕方ない 別の身代わりだ
いやぁ 俺のクマちゃんが…
Aaah! My teddy bear!
It'll be our turn, next!
次は僕らの番だ
Aah! He's discovered his Usa-chan!
ああ ウサちゃんが発見された
Who's the one who got my Usa-chan dirty?
僕のウサちゃん 誰が汚したの
"We'll leave his expression
to your imagination"
たたた…助けて モリ先輩
S-s-save us, Mori- senpai!
Usa-chan said that he absolutely
had to drink some tea.
ウサちゃんがどうしてもお茶を飲みたいって
He did? So that's why
his face is all dirty, huh?
そうか だからお顔が汚れちゃったんだね
あっ ケーキも食べるかなぁ
Oh, do you think he wants some cake, too?
"That's all it took?"
Honey- kun, what kind
of chocolate do you like?
ハニー君は どんなチョコレートが好き？
Mousse? Bonbons? I'll bet it's
chocolate cake that's your favorite, huh?
ムース？ボンボン？
やっぱりチョコレートケーキが好きなのかな？
Let's see... I like them all.
うんっとねぇ どれも幸せ
チョコもウサちゃんもみんなも大好きだもん
I love chocolate, Usa-chan,
and all of you!
Oh, how cute!
いやぁ 可愛い
Honey-senpai,
or Haninozuka Mitsukuni, age 17.
ハニー先輩こと 埴之塚光邦 17歳
Ouran Academy 3rd-Year, Class A,
registered in the Host Club.
桜蘭学院高等部3年A組 ホスト部在籍
Favorite things include cake,
chocolate, and bunnies.
好きなものはケーキにチョコにウサギさん
Possesses a loveliness
befitting a 3rd-Year,
三年生にあるまじきラブリーさで無敵を誇るロリショタ系
and boasts an unassailable
boy-Lolita quality.
Honey- senpai is in a good mood, huh?
ご機嫌ですね ハニー先輩
Thank goodness. We settled the
Usa-chan issue without any trouble.
よかった 何事もなくウサちゃんの問題が解決して
Honey-senpai's charm points
include the phrases
お菓子好きと可愛い物好きはハニー先輩のチャームポイント
"I love candy" and "I love cute things."
Or so everyone says,
ってことになってるんだけど
but for my part, I'm not sold on the
tepidity of his easygoing character!
私的にはこの安易なキャラ設定のぬるさには納得できない
As it stands, there's just
something missing!
これだけじゃいまいち何が足りない
ハニー先輩 そんなに甘いものばかり食べ続けて
Honey- senpai, if you keep eating
nothing but sweets like this,
you're bound to develop cavities.
虫歯になっても知りませんよ
It's okay. I make sure to brush my teeth.
大丈夫
ちゃんと歯磨きしてるもん
"Ow!"
Honey- senpai, don't tell me...
ハニー先輩 まさか…
It's nothing, really.
何でも…ない
Come on, open your mouth, please.
ほら 口開けて見みてください
Hold on.
ちょっと ハニー先輩 大人しく…
Honey- senpai, sit still.
いやあ～
It's nothing! It's nothing! No!
なんでもない なんでもない イヤだ
そう これよこれ！
Yes! That's it, that's it!
What was missing was this type of moe!
足りなかったものはこの萌え
Is it a cavity?
虫歯…ですか
Yeah.
Oowie! Ouchie! Oowie!
Ouchie! Oowie! Ouchie!
痛いよ 辛いよ 痛いよ 辛いよ 痛いよ 辛いよ…
No, I'm okay.
違う… 大丈夫
Tamaki...
環
Yeah, all right, understood.
はい 分かりました
Until Honey- senpai gets over his cavity,
all sweets are off-limits to him.
ハニー先輩は虫歯が治るまで甘いものは禁止
Further, in order to allow the
entire club to offer its support,
なお 部全体での協力体制としてしばらく
we ask you to temporarily refrain
from consuming any snacks within the club.
部内でのおやつは自粛とします
N-no, Takashi... I don't
want snacks to be off-limits.
イヤ…イヤだ 崇
おやつ禁止はイヤだ
I'm not in pain... I'm not in pain, okay?
僕 痛くない 痛くないから
Stop! That's my cake!
やめて… それ僕のケーキ…
It's off-limits.
禁止だ
And so, pitilessly, Honey- senpai's
hellish days had begun.
かくして無情にも
ハニー先輩の地獄の日々は始まったのでした
My, Honey- kun looks so tormented.
まっ ハニー君お労しい
The Host Club is to refrain
from having snacks.
ホスト部はおやつ自粛ですって
That must be quite a shock to him, huh?
さぞかしショックでしょうね
But, at the risk of being improvident,
he looks just like...
でも 不謹慎ですけれど あの姿はまるで…
"Bunny rabbit"
How lovely!
ラブリー
光邦 鞄
Mitsukuni, your bag.
I can carry it myself.
自分で持てる
Not that. Let me see it.
そうじゃない 見せてみろ
I was just looking at them.
I wasn't eating them.
見るだけだもん 食べないもん
I see. If you're just looking,
you can have this.
そうか 見るだけなら これをやろ
"Candy, half-off"
I'll keep the real ones.
本物は預かる
Aww, that's rough.
こりゃきついなぁ
"The 1st-Year trio came to watch"
Poor guy.
可哀想に…
You know, I didn't think that
Mori- senpai could be so firm.
しかし モリ先輩があそこまで押しが強いとはね
意外だったよね
You wouldn't expect it, huh?
I thought his principles kept him
ハニー先輩の困ることなんてしない主義だと思ってたけど
from doing anything to upset Honey- senpai.
To think that he could get his highness
to go along with him, too...
殿まで従わせちゃうとはねぇ
"The Host Club is now open for business"
Tamaki- kun, it's too bad.
環君 残念ですわ
I wanted you to have some of the
chocolate that was specially made
フランスから呼び寄せたうちの新しいパティシエ特製のチョコを
by our new pâtissier, which
my family hired in from France,
ぜひ召し上がっていただきたかったのに
but I understand that
you're refraining from sweets.
スイーツは自粛なんですってね
悲しまないで 姫
Do not fret, my princess.
For Honey- senpai's sake,
甘いものを我慢しているハニー先輩のために
we all want to help him in whatever way
we can to abstain from sweets.
僕らは少しでも協力してあげたいんです
My, sir, your friendship is so beautiful.
まぁ 殿方の友情って麗しいんですわね
Besides, I'm sure it's better this way.
それに きっとこれでよかったんだ
However delicious the chocolate may be,
in the face of my heated love,
どんなに美味しいチョコも
僕らの熱い愛の前には
it would probably melt,
and go to waste, as it vanished away.
もったいなくも 溶けて消えてしまっていたでしょうから
Tamaki- kun...
環君
Impressive, sir. Nice little act.
さすが殿
ナイス小芝居
You changed over quickly.
切り替え早っ
Buzz off.
抜かせ 如何なる時も優先すべきはお客さまの笑顔だろうが
Our priority at all times is to
keep our guests smiling, isn't it?
You guys watch yourselves, too.
Make sure not to give any kind of candy
お前たちも気を抜くなよ
"Grin"
どんな手を使ってもハニー先輩に菓子類を与えないように
to Honey- senpai, no matter
what tricks he resorts to.
Oh, incidentally, those instructions
come from Mori- senpai, not me.
あっ 因みに これはモリ先輩の指示だから 俺からじゃない
Kyoya- senpai seems to be
unusually enjoying this, huh?
鏡夜先輩 妙に楽しそうだなぁ
I can't hold it in any longer.
もう我慢できなくて
I just have to have you accept
my feelings for you, Mori- kun.
どうしても私 モリ君に自分の気持ちを受け入れてもらいたくて…
ダメですか
Can't you do that?
You don't, by any chance, have someone
else that's dear to you, Mori- kun?
もしかしたら モリ君にはもう誰が大切な方が…いらっしゃるの
いらっしゃるの…ね
There is, isn't there?
I... I...
私…私…
"Honey-senpai's 'get sweets' strategy
NO. 1: Use the cute."
た～かし
Takashi! It looks like my cavity got better!
僕 虫歯治ったみたい
そうか
Has it?
腫れも退いたし
The swelling has gone down, too!
Has it?
そうか
So, can I have just one piece of cake?
だ～から ケーキ一個だけ お願い
"Popsicle"
完治は遠そうだな
Full recovery still seems a long way off.
"Honey-senpai's 'get sweets' strategy
NO. 2: The indirect method"
"Gulp"
What are you drinking there?
何飲んでるの
D-Darjeeling tea, Honey- kun.
ダージリンですわ ハニー君
What are you eating?
何食べてるの
A-a spot of a sandwich.
サ…サンドイッチを少々…
You know what? I think some sweet candy
would go well with the tea.
僕はねぇ お茶には甘～いお菓子が合うと思うな
You know, like cake, or something.
Right? Right?
ほら ケーキとかさ
"Anticipation"
"Oh boy, oh boy!"
- Yes... I suppose it would...
- Oh boy, oh boy! Oh boy, oh boy!
そうですね 本当に
- It sure would...
- Oh boy, oh boy! Oh boy, oh boy!
We're sorry, Honey- kun!
ごめんなさい ハニー君
It's for your own sake!
あなたのためなのよ
W-wait!
あっ 待って
"Honey-senpai's 'get sweets' strategy
NO. 3: Pulling at heartstrings"
ハニー先輩
Honey- senpai...
Haru-chan, am I bad?
ハルちゃん 僕って悪い子？
神様に嫌われるようなことしたかなぁ
Have I done anything
to make God hate me?
Okay, look... just a little one, okay?
いいですか 少しだけですよ
A snack?
おやつ？
Yes.
Here.
"Kyoto kelp"
The color is kind of similar to chocolate.
少しチョコに似てるんですよ 色が
"Honey chose the wrong person"
"Candy prohibition order, day 3"
"Irritable"
He's on edge.
きてるなぁ
Somebody talk to him. He's scaring me.
誰か話しかけてよ
怖いよ
ああ お菓子の棚に…
Ah! He's headed for the candy shelves!
Relax. They're all empty, anyway.
安心しろ どうせ中は空だ
Kyoya- senpai, you seem
to be in a good mood.
鏡夜先輩 なんかご機嫌ですね
ああ またしても 俺のクマちゃんが…
Aah! Not my teddy bear again!
Ah, he's breathed his last.
あっ 息絶えた
He's given up after three days.
三日でギブか
ハ…ハニー先輩？
H-Honey- senpai?
食われてしまう
He's gonna eat me!
いてててててぇ…
Mitsukuni, don't take it out
on other people or things.
光邦 人や物に当たるな
You saved me. I got away
without being eaten.
助かった 食われずに済んだな
It's disgraceful.
見苦しいぞ
Takashi, you...
崇の… バカ
...idiot!!
Just a little bit won't hurt, right!?
You cheapskate! You hardhead!
ちょっとぐらいいいじゃん ケチンボ 石頭
Takashi... Takashi...
崇なんか…崇なんか 大嫌い
I hate you!
Ah, Honey- senpai!
ハニー先輩
Mori- senpai...
モリ先輩
Hey, are you okay?
ちょっと 大丈夫ですか
Takashi, I hate you! Takashi,
I hate you! Takashi, I hate you!
崇なんか大嫌い
Mori- senpai, you've taken
heavy damage there.
モリ先輩 大ダメージじゃん
But whether you had no choice,
or you're just self-destructing...
けど 仕方ないっつうか 自爆っていうか
...if you're going to be so depressed,
then you shouldn't have acted
んな凹むんなら
最初からあんな嫌われるような行動ばっか取らなきゃいいのに
in such a way to make him
hate you in the first place.
It was on purpose?
わざと…
Mori- senpai, by any chance,
were you trying
モリ先輩 もしかして
わざとハニー先輩に嫌われようとしてたんじゃないですか
to get Honey- senpai to hate you?
That couldn't be right, could it?
Having Honey- senpai
hate him would be like
ハニー先輩に嫌われるなんて
the end of the world for Mori- senpai.
モリ先輩にとっちゃこの世の終わりみたいなもんなのに
Why would he do it on purpose?
なんでわざわざ…
Well, in order to punish himself.
だから 自分を傷つけるために…
Am I wrong?
違いますか
Because it's all my fault.
俺の…せいだからだ
光邦の虫歯は 俺の不注意だ
Mitsukuni's cavity was
due to my carelessness.
I forgot to make him brush his teeth
before his nap, twice.
昼寝の前に歯磨きさせるのを二度ほど忘れてた
そんなのモリ先輩の責任じゃ…
But Mori- senpai, that's not your...
...responsibility, is it?
ないんじゃない
If Mitsukuni has to get
false teeth, I'll... I'll...
光邦が総入れ歯になったりしたら
俺は…俺は…
いや ならない ならない
No, that won't happen, that won't happen.
He's surprisingly negative, huh?
意外とネガティブなんですね
I wouldn't be able to live with myself
if Mitsukuni hadn't thrown me down.
光邦に投げ飛ばされるくらいじゃないと
俺の気が済まないんだ
The rough treatment
he got from Honey- senpai
ハニー先輩に厳しくしてたのは
was the punishment that
Mori- senpai gave to himself.
モリ先輩が自分自身に与えた罰だったんですね
つーか それって一瞬いい話っぽいけど
Still, while it may sound like
a nice story in the short run,
it's a bit much over
a single cavity, right?
虫歯一つでそんな…ねぇ
"You can't get more inept than that"
So, there you have it, Honey- senpai.
だっ そうですよ ハニー先輩
What will you do now?
どうしましょうね
I'm sorry!
ごめんね ごめんね 崇
I'm sorry, Takashi!
僕 もう歯磨き忘れない 忘れないよ
I won't ever forget
to brush my teeth again!
I won't forget!
"Several days later"
Several days later, after Honey- senpai
had recovered from his cavity,
数日後 虫歯の完治したハニー先輩は
rebounding from the candy
prohibition order up until then,
それまでのお菓子禁止令の反動で
he greedily stuffed his face full of cake.
貪るようにケーキを頬張るのであった
Kyoya- senpai looks oddly
depressed about something, huh?
鏡夜先輩 なんか妙に落ち込んでるなぁ
Honey- senpai's snack costs...
ハニー先輩のおやつ代って
...are just that expensive.
そんなにかかるんだ
Ahem...
Oh, could we have a new guest?
おや 新しいお客さまかな
モリ先輩のファンか
Are you a fan of Mori- senpai?
あっ この前の…
She's that girl from earlier...
I understand.
私 分かったんです
Mori- kun, I now know
who it is that is so dear to you.
モリ君の大切な人って誰なのか
Mori- kun, having the person
most important to you
モリ君の一番大切な人がハニー君だなんて…
being Honey- kun is so... it's so...
そんなの…そんなの…なんだか…すごく…
somehow, it's just so terribly...
いい～
...nice!
It would appear that you have just
taken your first step into a new world.
どうやらあなたも新しい世界に一歩を踏み出したようですわね
Mitsukuni, you have some cream...
光邦 クリームが…
ああ 萌え 萌えですわ ああ もう最高ですわ…
Moe! What moe! It's the greatest!
It's the greatest!
これ なんかハッピーエンドっぽいムードなんですが…
This seems to have the same
mood as a happy ending,
but are you really sure this outcome
should be viewed as a happy ending?
こんな落ちがハッピーエンドとして成立していいんでしょうか
Moe!!
萌えぇぇぇぇ
どうして環先輩がシルクハット被ってるんですか
Good grief.
どうして鏡夜先輩が茸の上にいるんですか
Tamaki-senpai, why are
you wearing a silk hat?
どうも一人だけ展開についてこれていないようだなぁ
Kyoya-senpai, why are you
on top of a mushroom?
It looks like you're not keeping up
with the storyline on your own, huh?
桜蘭高校ホストクラブ 来週も
Next time, "Haruhi in Wonderland"
お待ちしております
Ouran High School Host Club will
be waiting for you, next week!